The typicall steps to a git CLI
>>
firstly do 'git clone <link>'
then go into the directory 'cd <name of directory/repository'

once you create the changes you wish to do, simply do 'git add <files to add, or . (which adds all files)>'
then double check the files you wanted were added with 'git status'
when you are ready to stage your changes, run 'git commit -m "<your message here, one sentence, be as descriptive as possible. present tense.>"
lastly, when you are ready to push to a branch do 'git push <branch name>' or 'git push origin <branch name>' this will push to the specified branch.

You should 'git pull' by habit.
>>
to start a new branch to work on, do 'git checkout -b <branch name>' this allows you to work without stepping on peoples toes.
when you want to merge into main (main has your code), simply be on the branch you want to merge INTO main and do the steps above EXCEPT do 'git push origin <branch you want to merge into>'